<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on Joel Soroos</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on Joel Soroos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UpSet Charts Comparison</title>
      <link>/2020/07/07/cocktails-upset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/07/cocktails-upset/</guid>
      <description>Motivation For the May 26 2020 R4DS Tidy Tuesday data set, I explored UpSet charts, which simplify visualizing overlap of large numbers of sets. Laura Ellis has a useful explanation of how Venn and Euler diagrams become unwieldy for intersections of greater than two sets.
I analyzed which ingredients, as well as combination of ingredients, are most common in U.S. cocktail drinks.
 Source The cocktail ingredients data is originally from the Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Song Analytics</title>
      <link>/2020/05/02/spotify-song-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/02/spotify-song-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Spotify is an amazing app to play favorite music, discover new music and rediscover old favorites. In addition, the Spotify API provides free access to a wide array of data on songs, which R users can leverage via Charlie Thompson&#39;s spotifyR package. I wanted to learn more about my musical tastes while learning new R skills.
 1. Activate Spotify connection First step is to sign up for a free Spotify API developer ID and secret token.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite links</title>
      <link>/links/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/links/</guid>
      <description>Learning R  &amp;ldquo;R for Data Science&amp;rdquo; — seminal Tidyverse book by Hadley Wickham &amp;amp; Garrett Grolemund &amp;ldquo;Learning R Step by Step&amp;rdquo; - hard copy book by Richard Cotton Statistics with R — online Duke courses via Coursera R Programming — online Johns Hopkins class via Coursera Advanced R - advanced R primer by Hadley Wickham  Sourcing  Setting environmental variables Spotify API  Wrangling  Getting and Cleaning Data in R — online Johns Hopkins class via Coursera Data wrangling in dplyr - tutorials by Susan Baert Pivot wide &amp;amp; pivot long - new dplyr reshaping tools Regular expressions Simplify lists to data frames  Modelling  Distance matrixes Clustering  Visualizing Fundamentals  &amp;ldquo;Fundamentals of Data Visualization&amp;rdquo; — free online book by Claus Wilke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite R Packages</title>
      <link>/2019/11/15/favorite-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/15/favorite-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>Sourcing  readr - fast and friendly way to read rectangular data (i.e. csv, tsv) RODBC - SQL querying against relational databases readxl - importing Excel files including individual worksheets rvest - tools for working with http connections rio - simplify importing and exporting data across source formats datapasta - copy/paste data using clipboard   Exploring  skimr - displays summary statistics the user can skim quickly to understand their data dataexplorer - automated scanning and visualizing of each data set field   Wrangling  dplyr - transform and summarize data frames stringr - manipulate regular expressions and character strings lubridate - simplify working with dates and times glue - concatentate strings and/or data magrittr - set of operators to make code more readable such as the pipe janitor - simple functions for cleaning dirty data tidyr - transform data layout tidytext - simplify text mining   Modelling  broom - converts statistical model output to tidy data ggdenro - parses dendogram data into data frames   Visualizing  ggplot2 - R&#39;s famous package for beautiful graphics usibg the grammar of graphics ggmap - access Google API to download Google maps and geolocations ggraph - ggplot2 extensions for network diagrams and trees ggridges - density plots geofacet - visualize data for geographical regions via faceting with arrangement of panels mimicing original geographic topology ggupset - upset charts to visualize set intersections patchwork - combine charts gganimate - view chart evolution over time via animation scales - maps data to aesthetics, automatically determines breaks and labels for axes and legends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations</title>
      <link>/visualizations/visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visualizations/visualizations/</guid>
      <description>A collection of data visualizations I have built for fun using the R programming language. All visualizations are produced via code without post-processing. 
The examples source data from the weekly R4DS #TidyTuesday project, which is a community for R and tidyverse enthusisasts to practice and share ideas in wrangling, exploring and visualizing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>