<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Joel Soroos</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Joel Soroos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kmeans Clustering of Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>/2020/09/21/penguins-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/21/penguins-clustering/</guid>
      <description>In today&#39;s blog, I explore k-means clustering capabilities in R including algorithms, visualizations and methodologies to identify the optimal number of clusters (&amp;quot;k&amp;quot;).
K-means clustering is an unsupervised machine learning tool to group similar unlabeled data or to identify patterns outside of existing categorizations in labelled data. K-means is the most widely used unsupervised machine learning tool and considered &amp;quot;unsupervised&amp;quot; due to absence of labelled data in the analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpSet Charts Comparison</title>
      <link>/2020/07/07/cocktails-upset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/07/cocktails-upset/</guid>
      <description>Motivation For the May 26 2020 R4DS Tidy Tuesday data set, I explored UpSet charts, which simplify visualizing overlap of large numbers of sets. Laura Ellis has a useful explanation of how Venn and Euler diagrams become unwieldy for intersections of greater than two sets.
I analyzed which ingredients, as well as combination of ingredients, are most common in U.S. cocktail drinks.
 Source The cocktail ingredients data is originally from the Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Song Analytics</title>
      <link>/2020/05/02/spotify-song-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/02/spotify-song-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Spotify is an amazing app to play favorite music, discover new music and rediscover old favorites. In addition, the Spotify API provides free access to a wide array of data on songs, which R users can leverage via Charlie Thompson&#39;s spotifyR package. I wanted to learn more about my musical tastes while learning new R skills.
 1. Activate Spotify connection First step is to sign up for a free Spotify API developer ID and secret token.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Functions</title>
      <link>/2020/02/09/tidy-tuesday-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/09/tidy-tuesday-functions/</guid>
      <description>1. Most widely learned functions are in ggplot2 and dplyr packages.   package  n  percent      ggplot2  16  0.176    dplyr  9  0.099    base  6  0.066    stringr  5  0.055    ggimage  3  0.033    ggraph  3  0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite R Packages</title>
      <link>/2019/11/15/favorite-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/15/favorite-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>Sourcing  readr - fast and friendly way to read rectangular data (i.e. csv, tsv) RODBC - SQL querying against relational databases readxl - importing Excel files including individual worksheets rvest - tools for working with http connections rio - simplify importing and exporting data across source formats datapasta - copy/paste data using clipboard rtweet - Twitter API via R spotifyr - access Spotfiy API via R   Exploring  skimr - displays summary statistics the user can skim quickly to understand their data dataexplorer - automated scanning and visualizing of each data set field   Wrangling  dplyr - transform and summarize data frames stringr - manipulate regular expressions and character strings lubridate - simplify working with dates and times glue - concatentate strings and/or data magrittr - set of operators to make code more readable such as the pipe janitor - simple functions for cleaning dirty data tidyr - transform data layout tidytext - simplify text mining   Modeling  broom - converts statistical model output to tidy data factoextra - kmeans clustering algoriths, visualizations NbClust - index of 30 kmeans clustering optimal K methodologies ggdenro - parses dendogram data into data frames stats - assorted machine learning, statistics and probability algorithms   Visualizing  ggplot2 - R&#39;s famous package for beautiful graphics usibg the grammar of graphics ggmap - access Google API to download Google maps and geolocations ggraph - ggplot2 extensions for network diagrams and trees ggimage - adding custom images to charts ggridges - density plots patchwork - combine charts scales - maps data to aesthetics, automatically determines breaks and labels for axes and legends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>