<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Joel Soroos</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Joel Soroos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spotify Song Analytics</title>
      <link>/2020/05/01/spotify-song-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/01/spotify-song-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Spotify is an amazing tool to play favorite music, as well as discover new music or rediscover old favorites. The API in turn provides free access to a wide array of statistics on songs and albums in playlists.
 1. Activate Spotify connection First step is to sign up for a free Spotify API developer ID and secret token.
Second, you can either embed the Spotify login information directly in the script or assign to an enivronment variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Functions</title>
      <link>/2020/04/20/tidy-tuesday-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/20/tidy-tuesday-functions/</guid>
      <description>1. Most widely learned functions are in ggplot2 and dplyr packages.   package  n  percent      ggplot2  17  0.230    dplyr  10  0.135    base  4  0.054    ggraph  3  0.041    stringr  3  0.041    broom  2  0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite R Packages</title>
      <link>/2020/04/12/favorite-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/12/favorite-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>Sourcing  readr - fast and friendly way to read rectangular data (i.e. csv, tsv) RODBC - SQL querying against relational databases readxl - importing Excel files including individual worksheets rvest - tools for working with http connections rio - simplify importing and exporting data across source formats datapasta - copy/paste data using clipboard   Exploring  skimr - displays summary statistics the user can skim quickly to understand their data dataexplorer - automated scanning and visualizing of each data set field   Wrangling  dplyr - transform and summarize data frames stringr - manipulate regular expressions and character strings lubridate - simplify working with dates and times glue - concatentate strings and/or data magrittr - set of operators to make code more readable such as the pipe janitor - simple functions for cleaning dirty data tidyr - change the layout of data sets tidytext - simplify text mining   Modelling  broom - converts statistical model output to tidy data ggdenro - parses dendogram data into data frames   Visualizing  ggplot2 - R’s famous package for beautiful graphics usibg the grammar of graphics ggmap - access Google API to download Google maps and geolocations ggraph - ggplot2 extensions for network diagrams and trees ggridges - density plots geofacet - visualize data for geographical regions via faceting with arrangement of panels mimicing original geographic topology patchwork - combine charts gganimate - view chart evolution over time via animation scales - maps data to aesthetics, automatically determines breaks and labels for axes and legends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>