<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dataviz on Joel Soroos</title>
    <link>/tags/dataviz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dataviz on Joel Soroos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dataviz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite links</title>
      <link>/links/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/links/</guid>
      <description>Learning R  &amp;ldquo;R for Data Science&amp;rdquo; — seminal Tidyverse book by Hadley Wickham &amp;amp; Garrett Grolemund &amp;ldquo;Learning R Step by Step&amp;rdquo; - hard copy book by Richard Cotton Statistics with R — online Duke courses via Coursera R Programming — online Johns Hopkins class via Coursera Advanced R - advanced R primer by Hadley Wickham  Sourcing  Setting environmental variables Spotify API  Wrangling  Getting and Cleaning Data in R — online Johns Hopkins class via Coursera Data wrangling in dplyr - tutorials by Susan Baert Pivot wide &amp;amp; pivot long - new dplyr reshaping tools Regular expressions Simplify lists to data frames  Modelling  Distance matrixes Clustering  Visualizing Fundamentals  &amp;ldquo;Fundamentals of Data Visualization&amp;rdquo; — free online book by Claus Wilke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations</title>
      <link>/visualizations/visualizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/visualizations/visualizations/</guid>
      <description>A collection of data visualizations I have built for fun using the R programming language. All visualizations are produced via code without post-processing. 
The examples source data from the weekly R4DS #TidyTuesday project, which is a community for R and tidyverse enthusisasts to practice and share ideas in wrangling, exploring and visualizing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>